Eli...
Do you know much I love you?
How much I always want to protect you...
Do you want to go mad as much as I do?
I want you to know everything.
Lady Elianna!
I know you're in there!
Come out like a proper lady!
I'm telling you that now is *not* a good time!
Can I at least run away?
Lady Elianna!
Every single time, the pests come
just when we get to the good part.
Is this some sort of tanuki curse at work?
The Holy Night's Banquet Where the Butterflies Dance
Um...
I would like to have a talk with Elianna,
just the two of us.
Lady Sharon, there's no need to be shy.
Lady Sharon, what do you need
to talk to me about?
At the Holy Night's Banquet, please let me
be Prince Christopher's partner in your place.
You will be compensated, of course.
If you would be willing to trade with me,
I'll let you borrow this as thanks.
Could that... possibly be...
Yes, the ship's log of Captain Vigo,
also known as the King of the Seas,
written by the man himself.
Captain Vigo...
Historically, he was first to accomplish
the conquest of the eastern ship routes.
Because he died young and on foreign land
his name and achievements are given precedence
over the reality of his voyage,
and he's become a legendary figure.
What tales of adventure did he record?
How could you propose such a thing, Lady Sharon?!
My grandfather said I could use it however I wanted!
There are limits to these sorts—
Lady Elianna.
What do you say?
I obviously cannot give this to you,
but I can lend it to you while I'm staying here.
I know...
I cannot have it both ways.
Right... Of course.
I can't do that.
Wah?
Your silence in deciding was extraordinarily long,
and you look like you're about to break out in tears...
You're imagining things, Your Highness.
I have a fair idea of why you are so insistent
about myself being your partner, Lady Sharon.
However, is this something you decided on,
or is this the will of the Miseral Dukedom?
W-Well, I...
Lady Sharon decided this on her own.
Elen!
Please consider your position.
Lady Mireille even told you
to watch your speech and actions, did she not?
But...
But, this is wrong!
My sister Mireille is the celebrated
"Pearl Princess of Miseral"!
And yet...
She was married to a Count Lamond,
who's 25 years older than her,
then he passes away in the blink of an eye...
and she can't expect to get a marriage proposal.
Lady Mireille deserves happiness
more than anyone else in the whole country!
You mustn't take your anger out on books!
Come on!
It’s your fault for being here, Bibliophile Princess!
That's where Mireille belongs!
You care for nothing but books, right?
Then go hole yourself up in the library!
Lady Sharon.
I can't do that.
It's certainly true that I am a bookworm
who has no interest in anything but books, but...
the feelings that I have for Prince Christopher
are as real as anyone else's.
I could never give up my place
next to His Highness.
Lady Sharon.
Are you trying to spoil the friendship
between Miseral and Sauslind
with your own self-centered desires?
But...
We are beyond the point
where you can resolve things by crying.
You owe Lady Elianna an apology.
Lady Sharon, it seems you have Elianna all wrong.
Eli...
When you had just become my fiancée,
you sent away for books related to
medicinal herbs from each country, right?
Why did you do that?
I was curious about the pharmaceutical knowledge
of other countries.
Also...
I’d learned that research into treatments
for the Ashen Nightmare had come to a standstill.
I thought other books from other countries
might provide us an alternate perspective.
But that illness is already gone, isn't it?
It has only temporarily been resolved.
It may all happen again someday.
So you focusing on the Azul Region this whole time
was also due to research on the Ashen Nightmare?
That as well,
but in the fairy tales of the Azul Region,
there are a lot of stories about children without parents.
When I looked into it,
I learned that there were many villages
where the parents made a living
away from home like in the Corba Village.
I thought it was sad
that the families couldn't live together.
For that reason,
I thought it would be nice if there were something
to base their lifestyles on in the impoverished lands.
But isn’t that kind of...beyond your ability to fix?
We can't make every territory in the country prosperous.
As the nobility, "we can't do anything about that"
are words that must never leave our mouths.
The reason we are not exposed to the elements,
dress in beautiful clothing, and eat elaborate foods
is because that is all supported by the people.
Excuse me.
May I ask the reason the shells
from the Corba Village caught your eye?
Originally, it started when I heard from my brother
that the pigments used in the wall paintings
in prehistoric times were made from shells.
Then, you decided on Corba Village's Milulu clam?
Yes, but... as of right now,
I haven't found any use for it besides in paintings.
Did you talk about that in front of my mother too?
Huh? Yes.
Lady Sharon, do you understand?
Elianna, during these four years,
has advanced research on the remedy,
and searched for ways to enrich impoverished lands.
Even if she did not have the title
of fiancée of the crown prince,
I feel she would have done something.
That is precisely why
the people of Sauslind stand behind Elianna.
But...
Then why was it so widespread that the Yule Lovers
are Your Highness and Mireille's love story?
It's because you two have loved
each other since childhood, right?
That handwriting...
it's Mireille's!
I knew you two were still having intimate exchanges!
The "Yule Lovers" is a story
about Your Highness and Mireille!
Eli! That isn't the case at all.
Sit down.
He's like a husband resigned to confess to his affair.
And there's even hard evidence.
Glen, you seem like you want
permanent residence in Miseral.
I'll get you just the paperwork you need later.
Why only me?!
About that love story...
I've suspect there's a motive behind it.
A motive?
I hear that dukes who treated Lady Mireille so coldly
also caused damage to the national interest
in an accident at sea several years earlier.
They seem desperate to regain their honor.
And?
They set their sights on the popularity of Lady Mireille,
known as the "Pearl Princess,"
who is also supported by the citizens,
and it isn't odd that they would consider using her.
Use... Mireille?
I see.
If Lady Lamond weren't a widow,
this love story wouldn't be possible.
No way, Duke Lamond died...
and not due to an accident?!
Now, I also haven't looked that far into it,
and this is just speculation at the most.
That can't be...
I get it!
My sister Mireille requested help
from Your Highness in this letter, right?
Unfortunately, it isn't something as endearing as that.
It seems Lady Mireille has been doing
her own investigating into this matter
and noticed my own investigations.
We made deals and mutual disclosures and she decided
"We will settle Miseral's internal problems on our own,
and there is no need for any help at all."
Quite bold of her, actually.
At the same time, she says, "The one who is like
a dear sister to me may cause a bit of trouble,
but I expect you will be tolerant
of the fanciful tales of a child."
She concludes by saying
she sincerely congratulates me for the marriage
with the daughter of the Marquis Bernstein, my first love.
I deeply apologize.
I will offer my apologies on Lady Sharon's behalf.
I'm afraid I must make an excuse,
but Lady Sharon's mother is sickly,
and Lady Mireille is the one who has taken care
of her since she was a child.
Consequently, that has led to excessive behaviour,
but we ask for your kindness and generosity.
This is just like "The Piglet's Beloved Dimples".
Oh, I know that tale.
There was an orphaned piglet named Rue.
Rue was scrawny and looked unappetizing,
and the people around him
didn't think he'd fetch a good price,
but a young girl who was orphaned just like Rue
raised him and showed him kindness.
The girl fell in love with the son of a Lord.
Rue knew of the girl's desire
to catch the boy's eye no matter what it took,
so he thought hard about it.
He knew what to do!
He would become the village's
most delicious-looking pig and catch the eye of the lord!
It was all because he wanted to see the happy face
of the girl who had dimples when she smiled...
So, what happened to the piglet?
It's a pig, so it got eaten in the end, right?
You're really heartless, aren't you?
From that letter, I know that Lady Mireille
even now still yearns deeply for Earl Lamond.
The actions you take on account of others
will not necessarily produce only good results.
They wore on me as well this time.
For the piglet's... ah, pardon me, for Lady Sharon's sake,
let's forget this ever happened.
We thank you, Your Highness.
Now, Lady Sharon, let's go.
Who is he calling a "piglet"?!
She is very much like a piglet.
Ah, Elianna.
It's as if the room has instantly become more dazzling.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Yes, like—
You're like a single rose, just begun to bloom.
Oh, my.
The red shading may be a bit too strong...
There's still room for improvement.
My mother dyed that dress
using the dye of the Milulu clam.
Oh?
I had it tailored by my personal designer
based on what you said.
Whether or not the Corba Village and
the Azul Region can become prosperous
depends on your publicity.
Give it your full effort.
Queen Henrietta...
It's all right if I occasionally make use of your ideas
instead of Chris doing it all the time.
Do you hate that Lady Dauner tried to make
a fashionable dress with Eli's idea so much?
Of course I do.
And you're responsible too!
Do you know of anyone who would just stand idly by
as their own ideas were poached?
N-No...
And making such a tacky dress...
Since it originally was your idea,
I had no choice but to agree it was nice...
But make sure you use the power you display
when protecting others for yourself as well.
I don't believe that people who can't value themselves
are able to protect others.
Yes...
Thank you very much, Mother.
I was reprimanding you for your behavior.
Who would thank someone for that?
Yes.
Now, about Sara...
Yes?
I am also to blame for disobedience
by a maid of the inner palace.
It seems like the one who leaked your words
was from a frequent company visitor,
and was in communication with the Dorud Company.
The inefficiencies in the vetting process of those
who frequently visit is also under my area of authority.
I must offer you an apology.
There's no need...
Sara was removed from the maids,
and I have demoted her.
She'll be starting from scratch in her new position,
but when she returns,
she must become your devoted maid.
Yes, Mother.
Had you only dealt with
your own political opponents from the start,
this would not have happened.
Oh, that hurt a little.
You dressing Eli up is merely an extension
of your own interests, right?
What a disrespectful son I have!
If you are envious, you need simply
and honestly admit that you are.
Pardon me?
Why must I be envious of my mother's silly hobby
of dressing up younger ladies?
And what, pray tell, are you trying to imply?
Elianna.
If you're calling my wife "Mother,"
what will you call me?
Well, since you’re the king, ‘Your Majesty’?
Eli.
You can call me your refined and kind uncle, if you'd like.
What utter nonsense are you spewing?
You're going to die a lonely death
as the bachelor you are, Uncle.
It's taken four years of my life to get that name.
How about you take the same time as I did and earn it?
It took quite a lot to get that name.
Elianna.
I heard that recently, you used your influences
in various ways for the Azul Region.
I commend you for those efforts, and I was thinking
I would give you some kind of reward.
Oh, it was nothing at all.
Well, from the beginning of the year,
red dresses dyed with Milulu clams
will no doubt be in vogue.
Your achievements will certainly become something huge.
No need to be so modest, just accept it.
But we don't know if this will make life
safe and secure in the Azul Region.
There was one other ink that you found, right, Eli?
Eh? Yes, but that was...
I've made use of it over there.
From next year on,
I want to make it one of the Holy Night's Banquet specialties.
That's why you should get your reward.
Well then, may I take a short rest
when the Holy Night's Banquet is over?
A break?
Yes. Well...
I'd like to read some books.
Books?
Yes.
I've got a stack of many books I'd like to read.
There would be no greater reward
than being able to take a break, Your Majesty!
Very well.
Lady Elianna Bernstein.
I grant you a vacation, and I vow to you
not a single soul shall stand in the way of that.
Thank you, Your Majesty!
You are way too soft with Elianna!
Not nearly as soft as you are...
Eli... I'm sorry.
Hm?
I haven't kept the promise that I made to you
at the beginning at all.
Lady Elianna,
the only things you'll need to do
are stay by my side and read your books.
I decided for myself that I would be by your side.
There are things I ought to do to that end,
so it's all right.
I've only made you put up with everything,
and I am a disappointment of a prince.
Your Highness, to me you're a dashing prince.
You’re utterly amazing—more than I even deserve.
In my eyes... you’re the best prince in the world.
Say that once more, Eli.
Once is enough.
I wish I could get a reward, too.
I'd like to have some of your time.
Is that too demanding?
No, that's fine...
Really?
Of course.
That's a promise, Eli.
Your Highness, is something happening here?
Yeah. It's a special touch for tonight.
Everyone,
I promise you all that this Holy Night's Banquet
will remain in your heart for eternity.
Keep your eyes peeled. You’re in for a real treat.
Quench the braziers!
Ready, and...
I have a present for you - leather binding
I'm sure it will suit you more than anyone else
Your Highness, what is this?
It’s the luminescent ink you created.
u
re
shii
I can see the usual embarrassment on your face when you're happy
u
re
shii
There was a milky ink made from mixing
the Milulu clam pigment with different minerals, right?
I want to see your smile again
It was something that glowed in the darkness.
mou
i
kkai
mou
i
kkai
Once more, once more, ask me for something
mou
i
kkai
Do you remember the laboratory
from the ghost commotion recently?
mou
i
kkai
mo
to
Yes.
me
tsu
zu
When night falls, a ghost with a pale glow
wanders around the laboratory.
The time that I spent together with you so far
a
na
ta
to
That's what it really is.
This could also be a solution
ga
na
to combat the steep price jump
for firewood and charcoal in the winter.
The memories etched into my mind
The present that's even more wonderful than the day we met
The days that we'll have in the future
Eli, you’re like the wind that pushes my sails forward.
I want to see them
A single word packed full with dreams has power
We sway, we sway, but that word binds us together
yu
re
Thank you, my dear, sweet Bibliophile Princess.
Side-by-side, side-by-side our two shadows
I'm pleased that I can help you, my beloved prince.
They sway, they sway, and melt into one
Let's see these lights together again next year.
ke
te
ku
And I look forward to the new year with you,
my soon-to-be wife.
Yes, I pray that the new year treats us favorably,
my soon-to-be husband.
Eli, the weather's nice today.
Would you like to take a little walk in the courtyard?
In that case, let's go to the conservatory.
If you're reading your book next to me...
It's all right, Prince Christopher.
What book were you reading?
It's the most recent Eastern pharmaceutical research.
There are some very interesting accounts of...